At the Synagogue Church of All Nations,
Prophet TB Joshua leads
the congregation in mass prayer.
And the power of God immediately comes on the scene
and uproots whatever that is not of God in their lives.
He begins to prophesy and exposes the hand
of the devil in the lives of the people. Let's listen to him.
There is a brother, you have tatoo
everywhere; I think I touched you.
With your tattoo, here.
You're a criminal,
you are wearing dark, dark.
That spirit is tormenting you,
disturbing you, okay?
TESTIMONY TIME
Good morning, church!
Glory be to God.
My name is Tebogo.
I'm from South Africa.
I am 37 old.
I am a firstborn from the three
boys that have been given birth to this
wonderful woman here right beside me.
This is my mum.
Tebogo & Mother - Prophecy Testimony
Yes, I'm thankful to be here, all glory be to God.
Last weekend Prophet TB Joshua
actually prophesied and called me
from the crowd.
I was actually sitting right at the back
and I didn't want to sit in the front.
But he actually called me and he
told me that, this is something
I never told nobody and I think
nobody knew about that.
But he just called me and told me
that I used to live a life of a crime,
and that this spirit is actually tormenting me
and it's going to disturb me and give me trouble.
That's when I came out.
Yes, indeed it is true.
Though some of the things that I'm going to say,
this is the first time that I will be telling the truth.
Even my mum I never told her the truth.
This is the first time that she'll
be hearing me saying this,
live on camera.
It actually started when it was around 1996.
I was in my high school year.
Raised as a boy with good values,
being in high school, getting straight A's from school...
By then I was a good boy in the house doing all chores,
being good in the house.
But every time I went to the street,
everything changed though -
I had to be like a crook in the neighborhood
due to being growing under the older guys
that used to stay next to a park.
So they used to sell drugs and have cars.
So they taught us how to car wash,
and how to open a car without
a key and things like that.
So we sold weed and drugs
in that mini park.
So that's how I got introduced to
the street life.
So at what age were you when you actually began
the issue of selling drugs and
meeting with these older gang members?
At what age were you?
I was still young, it was my early
years of studying in high school.
I think I was 16 - 17 years old.
We actually started just looking at them,
doing what they do, like having guns out there,
washing cars and doing all these things.
So they taught us how to -
like I said - open a door of a car
without having the keys,
and knowing which cables you can
can start a car without using a key.
And we used to sell drugs by
the parks that we used to be playing games.
By the park we used to do recreational things.
We used to play, tumbling and all that,
but then we would be around the park and selling drugs for them.
Me having that and my mum
not knowing what I was doing -
I would go back and I would be a good boy in the house
but every time I went outside in the street,
those are the things I had to do -
doing the material and vanity...
As a youth, those are the things that
were actually exciting me as a group.
So I was a junior member of a gang,
as you would like to say.
That's when we started being in the park, we started robbing people with knives.
But at first I was young, we would
drop like vulnerable people,
like people who are drunk or people
who are a couple which is chilling
at a park. We just robbed them their belongings like that.
And then it went to be like graduating like having a gun,
of which a gun is something that I...
The first encounter with a gun
with me and my friends -
I think it was in 1997 or towards 1997 or so,
I was still in high school with the
best friend of mine
and we actually disarmed the
gun from a friend of mine -
the other friend of mine who came with
his father's gun and he showed us the gun
But we took a gun from him.
But we had a fight - me and my friend again
because we actually didn't know
who was supposed to keep the gun.
I wanted to keep it - he wanted to keep it too.
So we kept the gun between
us - sometimes it would be in my house,
sometimes it would be in his house.
And that's how we ended up like selling drugs,
after selling drugs we started
disarming other people
who were selling drugs in our community
because we wanted actually to own the territory.
So if we knew that you were selling drugs in our community,
then we would come through to you and rob you
with a gun - from knives to guns.
And then, having money
for drugs and things like that
we actually moved on to disarming
other guys who had guns.
And that brought us some more of other gangs.
By then I was still young,
I was still being used because I didn't have fear.
I wouldn't have fear, I didn't hesitate
in doing things;
even if I was scared I didn't hesitate in doing things.
So I would disarm and have a gun
but my mum didn't know anything,
she thought I was just a good boy.
She can tell you, I was just a good boy.
Everything was just sweet and
stuff like that.
Sometimes I would be in
prison - in and out -
I wouldn't even tell her. l could stay
in prison for two or three days,
but I didn't tell her.
A couple of times - in and out,
in and out and selling drugs.
She would hear that I was selling drugs
but she heard that at the later stage.
That's when I was actually in the university.
Because I graduated from varsity as well
and after graduating from varsity,
that's when I was older and I got a car.
And even when I bought a car,
I told her: "Mama, I bought a car."
But she didn't know that the car was stolen.
But I told her that I bought a car,
and she knew that I bought a car.
I would come to her, she would help
me with money
and things like that.
I would go back and spend it
the way I spent it.
Okay, so you said from the
robbery using both knives and guns,
you now graduated also to stealing cars.
Can you explain how you would
go about that?
Well, stealing cars like it was with the guns and knives -
we would go for vulnerable people, we would go
for places where people don't know us.
For instance we would go for a neighborhood
where they didn't even know us.
We would just go there in the
morning and we would go and rob -
maybe like a drunk guy in a pub
who is about to go to his car.
So as he is going to his car,
we just pop up and just take him
put him in a boat and go to him in a boat, tie him up.
We take a car and just park it somewhere
in a mall for the whole day
and just leave it there. We stand away
just looking at the car for the cops to come through.
After one day or two days without
cops then we know that it is not bad.
By then there were no these things of trackers
and things like that.
So it was easy for us to get cars.
Our brother is giving this confession
to confirm that word of prophecy
he received last week that he
was involved in a life of crime.
And he's saying that what he is confessing right now
his mother is actually hearing
it for the first time.
Because when you went back
to your house you would pretend,
you would be a good boy in the
house involving yourself in various chores.
But your mum would not be knowing that outside
you were living this very criminal lifestyle, is that right?
Yes, sir. My mum didn't know about the
criminal lifestyle that I was living.
And I think it was after when things
got really bad for me.
Because at some time I was in and out of prison
but there was a point when I was in prison
and I thought I had some previous things that
I did and have been in prison.
So me being in prison this time -
they would actually bring back my file and
see that I had previous things that I did in my life,
so I had to go for a longer period at that time.
That's when I went to prison and being in prison
I had to learn the ways of surviving,
so I had to study ways of having tattoos,
my first tattoos was having it in prison.
Having RAF3 tattoos, having
it right at the bottom of my legs.
And then I had to know how to survive there inside
being a cleaner, having food and things
like roll on, lotions, weed, cigarettes.
So I had access to these things since
I was in the passage being a cleaner.
So that's when I was introduced into doing tattoos.
But then, that love of tattoos came from
the time when I studied from Fine Arts at school,
I used to do fine arts, conceptual study,
History of art and things like that.
We just want you to explain that aspect
in prison very clearly - you said, when
you were in prison, you found a way of
getting things of surviving in prison.
Can you tell us, was there a form of initiation
into a certain gang whilst you were there in prison
or how did you find your way in
prison to have such things?
Yeah, there are rules in prison.
There was a paper that they pluck
at the back of the door
when you go in.
It's like they don't force you to join the gang;
they don't force you to be a member of a gang.
But there are rules that if you have any complains,
if they come in a morning and come to you,
if you have any complains, you can tell the waders
that these guys are troubling me or this guy did this.
but then I had ways to get things,
I had sheets, I had roll on
and I had Colgate.
These are the essentials, very
important that you need in jail.
So if the new guys come in they would clean for us
and if they need something
out, they exchange for that.
And that's when I really saw that I needed my mum,
and that's when I called her.
And she came through, she always came through
and we cried together.
And you know, I didn't like the life
I was living because like I said I
have two brothers that I left at home.
Okay, so our brother is explaining
because of this lifestyle,
he was going in and out of prison.
And he was actually in prison for a long time as a
result of the activities he was involved in.
And brother, can you just explain
to us, even after coming out of prison,
would you find you still going back
to those same criminal activities
to get money even after being in prison
and served a prison sentence?
Yeah, it was not easy because you know these things you do,
you often find a sense of belonging.
So I tried so many things even in prison,
I tried joining the Islam or
study Hari krishna.
At some point I was a Rasta, I smoked weed
and sold drugs - a whole lot of drugs.
So there was a way that I would
often go back and bounce back to that.
Because even when I came back out of prison
I found that people came into my house
and told me that they needed drugs.
So having a lot of people come into
my house that they needed drugs,
I saw an opportunity that maybe I
should go back and have these things.
And then I had drugs and then at some point
I was working through the canvas and
I would travel a whole lot of places
and I got hold of having the professional machines
of doing like tattoos.
Since I learned that in prison of doing tattoos
and knowing that I was good in
drawing and doing these things
then I bought these tattoos kits
and I was a tattoo artist at some point.
Okay, was there ever a time after coming out of prison
that you involved yourself in an
operation whereby you're actually
almost caught or you were sustained an injury
in the process of robbery operation
that you were undergoing?
Yeah, I would call that the biggest turn of my life
because there are certain things
that happened in my life
that, like they call it 'karma'.
Like you do bad things and bad things will follow you.
So there are certain things that
I did that they happened to me
and when they happened, it was not a surprise to me.
Because I used to rob people and I was once robbed.
I used to have guns and I was once shot.
You know, like being shot; like right now
I got my ankle is actually fused.
And this is the first time that my
mum will be hearing this
from here because even when I told her,
I told her a different story.
But this is the first time that she hears.
I was actually involved in a robbery
with a few guys.
We actually went and robbed the
other guy for his van
and a couple of cell phones and a
couple of laptops in a basement.
It was around Johannesburg in oriental plaza.
We robbed the guy - it was 2008.
I think it was on a 23rd of March.
We were three guys, I had a gun with me by then.
This other guys had guns but they
needed more guns to go and do the job,
so they called me and we went there.
Right when we went there we took the
car and we took everything,
we took the money, I took the money on me,
I had everything on account on me,
and the other guy just shot.
He made a shot, he shot the other guy on the leg -
the guy who was there, whom we robbed.
And then there was a sound of a gun
and there were the security guards around the area.
And there were cops and there was a chase,
they chased us and then we actually
left the car on the road
and we ran - everybody went his own way.
And then they chased me, the security
guard who was chasing me - behind me
and the other friends of mine - I don't
know if they were ever get caught or what.
The other guy who was chasing me
with a motorbike, I was having a gun -
I pointed him with a gun and he
actually moved away from me.
And then right there, when I was
running, I took a ride and I saw a flat.
It was next to the oriental mall Plaza flat,
I went in that mall.
Not in a mall, in a flat; I went into a flat
and I went in and I just closed the door there by the flat.
Right there when I closed the door by the flat,
there was a door and at the bottom
of the door there was a glass there.
So I just closed and I sat there,
and I closed the door with my leg.
And then I sat there and they thought
probably I have just passed
because I saw them, a few of them passing through.
But right then there was a guy who just came in,
I think the guy who stayed in the
same flat that I was in,
because I found a door open -
I was the one who closed the door.
So the guy who was staying there
wanted to push the door
for him to enter in a flat and I was there,
and he saw that there were
cops around and then he leaned a bit
and he saw me. Right when he saw
me, that's when he told her cops:
"Okay, the guy is there".
I heard him say the guy is there.
I tried to run but I had a shot.
Then that's when they shot me on an ankle
and I ran, I ran, I dragged myself, I dragged myself.
Just next to the building there was a
Mosque, it was around 5 o'clock.
I think that was a time where
they were about to start service,
so I went in there, I dragged myself,
I took my gun, I put it in a jacket.
I wrapped it with a jacket.
I wrapped my leg, but when I looked
at my leg - it was wobbling.
I felt like...
It was my first encounter of being shot,
so I felt like my feet was going to...
I felt that was a terrible pain.
It is was really drastic.
So I dragged myself and sat
behind the door at the mosque.
So they were passing through. Inside the mosque,
there's was a guy who is singing on top
and they just passed him through.
So I kept on asking for water
from these guys
and I drank a lot of water.
And at this point your foot was
heavily bleeding from the gunshots?
Yes, I was heavily bleeding, that was the reason
I took a jacket and wrapped my leg with a jacket
for them not to see the jacket; so
they probably thought it was a
begger or something.
So they gave me some water, some
of them just passed me there.
But then it was a time for the
service to end, then they went out.
And I went out and I dragged myself,
by then it was around quarter past six.
I'm not sure but it was past 6 in the afternoon.
I dragged myself and sat just outside the building -
there was a place where I could hide myself;
I just hid myself there.
Next to that mosque was another
building where there was a
motorbike fix store; there were
other guys who were fixing motorcycles.
I think these guys were coming for a night shift.
So they came in there, and when
they went in, they saw me there.
And they asked me: "What's happening?"
and I told them - I lied to them again -
I told them: "No! I was robbed and I was shot,
Please, I need help?
Can you call ambulance for me?"
But the other guy told me: "No, aren't
you the guy who was there around?"
Because he saw actually there were cops around.
So by then I couldn't lie, so I told him: "Yes,
I am the guy, and I pulled out cash from my pockets.
I think I pulled out three thousand or something."
I gave them all the money I had,
I told them: "I am the guy, please, can
you help me and call me ambulance?"
And I stayed there till the ambulance
came around 12 o'clock at midnight.
Then the ambulance took me, I went
to Helen Joseph's Hospital.
Right there in Helen Joseph's Hospital
they came with a scissors,
they tried to cut my clothing and all that
because I was heavily bleeding, but
I got a chance - I took a gun again,
I hid it with my jacket, I put it right there
where my clothing and my belonging can be -
in like a small cabinet just next to my bed.
And I went to theater and I came
back. When I came back,
I found a gun was still there, and
I stayed there and I called my girlfriend.
I have two kids with my wife,
I was staying with her then.
I called her to come and get the gun.
She came and got the gun from the place.
Okay, so we're listening to this
life experience of our brother.
He said during one of these robbery operations
he was actually shot in the ankle
and taken to hospital and he actually lied there
that he had been attacked whereas
he was actually the one involved in
the robbery operation.
And brother, how long were you in
the hospital as a result of this
gunshots in your ankle?
I stayed in the hospital for about nine months.
Because you actually had to go through like operations.
I think I had to go for three operations.
But my mom used to come through and visit me there,
and she was a believer, she would pray for me.
Well, there were evangelists and
people who would pray for me around there.
But I wouldn't want to listen to
them because I was fed up.
But I didn't know I was angry at God, I asked God:
"Why did You do this to me, I'm a good boy.
I'm a first graduate and all this,
why are You doing this to me?"
So I was just fed up, I didn't want to hear prayers.
But when she came through - "she" is my mum -
when she came, I would listen to her and she would pray for me.
Okay, so as our brother said earlier
our mother is actually hearing
the truth behind this incident for the first time.
She was under the impression that her
son was attacked in a robbery operation.
Hence the gun wound on his leg whereas today
he's confessing for the first time
that he was actually the one who
perpetrated robbery operation.
So brother even after you came out
from hospital with this injury to your
ankle - did this mean you still continued this life of
selling drugs and these criminal activities?
It was a turning point because I felt
like there was nothing I could do.
I used to skate, I used to play basketball,
I'm an artist so I needed to climb
stairs and things like that,
so my leg was very important to me.
But to me, I asked myself like: "What next?"
I thought that maybe I would die,
if I do something else - I would die.
But I bounced back, I went back to the neighborhood,
I went back to selling drugs again.
But then I sold drugs, and then
I continued doing tattoos again.
But I still had a gun with me again.
Okay, so now you said that you actually
became a tattoo artist, that you learned
about tattoos whilst you're in prison.
Could you just explain to us
more about the tattoos that you put all over your body?
I would do tattoos - I don't know,
if maybe I could show you?
Tebogo & Mother - Prophecy Testimony
So our brother is explaining that he actually
put tattoos across his entire body.
As he said, he was a tattoo artist.
And this is exactly as the man of God
prophesied in the word of prophecy -
he said, there's a brother there that
has tattoos all over his body,
And this is what we're seeing now.
So just tell his brother, what prompted you to be doing such?
Well, my tattoo was...
Like I said, I was angry at God,
there's a whole lot of things that happened to me
and I was angry at God, hence
I did a Lord's prayer on my cheek.
I did some wings on my neck,
I did a whole lot of tattoos all over my body.
And I came back. When I came back,
I continued selling drugs.
And then something happened to
me again. At some certain point
I was with my girlfriend, she
bought a car and I was chilling just
next to my house at the front of my gate.
And I was hijacked.
They actually tried to hijack us, me and my girlfriend.
There were four guys who wanted
to hijack and I was nabbed six times.
And I stayed in prison, I was knifed right here,
in the middle of my throat.
And I was knifed here on my nerve.
I was knifed here in the middle.
I think, at the back... And she knows
and she came through again.
She prayed for me right there again.
So what you were doing to others
now actually happened to you
and you were attempted to hijack your car,
and you were stabbed six times with a
knife when you're with your girlfriend?
So what you were doing to others
now came back and happen to you?
Yes, sir.
So can you just tell us, so today to the
glory of God, we can actually see you
standing in the presence of God with your mom
here the Synagogue Church of All Nations.
Could you just tell us,
how did it happen that you came to be here in the Synagogue Church of All Nations today?
Well, I used to be in denial. Actually she's a believer,
she always her she always prayed,
whenever I came through.
I don't know how she knew that
but every time I came through and was
about to leave the house,
she used to pray for me, and she gave me some
TB Joshua's books to go and read at home.
And every time I came back she asked me:
"Did you read those books?"
But I started to read those books
and I started to read the books.
And that right then, I met someone - while she was praying for me -
I met someone in the hospital before I got discharged,
who actually told me that I should actually
tell my story to someone in order for me to get healed.
So that's how I got here.
Okay, can you explain, when your
mum initially introduced you
to the Synagogue Church for All Nations, Emmanuel TV,
what was your reaction initially
when she introduced you to these things?
I didn't believe it at all.
So I would watch it, I mean would
watch Emmanuel TV the whole day.
And she knows, I would complain to her.
And when she went out, I would change the channel and watch some other things.
And when she came back, we
would watch Emmanuel TV.
But I would ask her: "Are we going
to watch this thing the whole day?"
Those were the things I would say to her.
But now I do, we sit together and we watch it on video.
Okay, so initially you were....
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
So initially you were very skeptical,
but your mum kept persisting
and encouraging you. And what finally,
maybe there was something you
saw on Emmanuel TV or experience
you had that finally convinced you
that you too should come here?
Well, she's the one who actually shone the light on me,
she told me: "I know you, I gave birth to you,
I know you are a good boy, and I miss that good boy in you."
You know, so that thing would make me very sad.
Because I wanted to see her smile,
I wanted to make her proud.
So immediately when I saw that...
I looked at myself, and I was like full of tattoos.
So I would ask myself...
And she told me, because she used
to come here and come back.
And she told me: "I've been to the
Synagogue Church of All Nations,
It's beautiful, there is power there,
you should come through there".
But I'd ask her how would they accept
a guy like me - I am full of tattoos?
I meant how could I enter in the Lord's house?
So I was a full of hesitation
and in denial of that.
So you thought that you would not
be accepted in the church
because of your appearance with
the tattoos all over your body?
Indeed, but then it happened differently.
Even if I was in denial,
but at some point I was tired of the street,
I wanted to make her happy - she was
always crying.
When I met her, she was not having
a smile and I missed that from her.
She was my best friend of all,
you should see us in the house.
She's the best. So I missed
that, so then I actually told her,
one day I told her that...
She told me that we should go
and I told her I want to go.
And she thought I was lying, and
I told her: "Yes, I am going to go".
She gave me money to go and do my passport
I ate the money, and she called
me again, and I didn't answer her calls.
But after some time I answered her call again,
and I agreed to come through here
and then we came in here.
But right at the airport - I was having tattoos
all over my body and I was wearing a t-shirt.
This our mother who was
our coordinater actually gave us T-shirt:
'My love is in heaven' with a big red heart,
and I was having tattoos all over my body,
so I felt like this is a contradiction.
I would look at people around me,
how they were looking at me in the airport
and in the plane and things like that.
But when you finally arrived, just tell
us what you experienced
when you came down to the church?
What I experienced here is something
I've never experienced in my life.
Because when I came here,
the guy who came to collect us from the airport -
he drove there, when I just came in.
He just gave me a hand and said: "Yes sir, how are you?"
And that was the first thing - I've never been called 'sir'.
He just said: "Yes sir, how are you sir?"
I was like: "I'm good".
But I was still bitter, he sai: "Good morning!"
I didn't answer him because I didn't
know what he meant.
So we came together with him,
but the guy didn't even ask me about my tattoos,
he didn't even look at me funnily
and I still meet him even now.
So you saw the initial love and acceptance
and then when you came down to the church - just tell us, what happened
as you arrived here at the church
and when you came to the Sunday service?
When I arrived in church, they showed
us the place where we should go to sleep.
But I would stay there where we just sleep.
I wouldn't come here to church, I would just stay there.
But there were people who were
still looking at me in a different way.
But you know, I didn't know but
when I came here -
we would sit in a dining room, we would discuss,
we would look at people
and hear testimonies on TV -
that I thought I was the worst,
but when I looked at other testimonies,
that's when I felt like...
Amen! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ,
that's how the testimonies of others
really inspired our brother.
And brother, on Sunday we witnessed
the clip as you sat down at the church
and the man of God gave that prophecy -
can you describe what happened
on that day when you received the prophecy
and ever since then the changes in your life?}
Well, I was still in denial because
even when he called me,
the other evangelist sister...
Prophet TB Joshua came and touched me.
But you know, due to I was still
in denial nothing happened.
I just stood there, he touched me but I
was still in denial because I didn't know what was happening.
I was confused about what was happening around.
You know, but then when these things happened, when he called me out,
nobody knew about my life, and he when he said that,
I just came out because I really felt it.
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
And to the glory of God, brother - it has
been one week now,
ever since that encounter, what are the
changes you've experienced in your life?
I have experienced love, tolerance.
As a youth, you have to live like a life of a movie,
and when you're watching a movie
at the end of the movie not nice.
So I was living like that, but when I came here,
I would go to Bible classes, meet
people around, everybody greets...
You go to sleep, nobody steals,
but nobody is told not to steal.
Things like that, those are the
things that matter to me most.
Amen! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
So you're now living a completely
new life. That spirit that was disturbing you
to rob, to steal, to take drugs,
sell drugs has completely gone.
Yes, I can really confess now
and say that Jesus Christ is my Savior.
Tebogo & Mother - Prophecy Testimony
I used to think that I could be saved
by certain things, but it's all vanity.
Amen! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
And brother, we know that your past is over
and you're completely out of your past life.
For the glory of God, you mentioned
earlier that you actually have tattoos
all over your body could you just
actually show us clearly the extend
of those tattoos all over your body,
so people can really see
what the Lord has done for you?
Tebogo & Mother - Prophecy Testimony
So once again, we're just showing this so that people of God
can understand what Jesus Christ
has really delivered our brother from
that life he was living. And he said earlier
that as someone with tattoos all
over his body
he felt that he would not actually
be accepted in the church environment.
He felt she would be looked down upon
or condemned because of his appearance.
But to the glory of God when he arrived at the Synagogue Church of All Nations. What he
experienced was love, acceptance and care.
And that really touched him, for
him to have seen such a reception
in the house of God and as a result, when
the word of prophecy came forth,
he realized that what the man of God said was something he had never told anyone.
He has never disclosed his past
life even to his own mother.
But when the word of prophecy came forth
that there's a man with tattoos all over his body
who was a criminal that touched his heart.
He came forward and ever since
then to the glory of God
he has been completely free from
that spirit that was disturbing him,
pushing him and to crime and pushing
him into taking drugs, selling drugs,
armed robbery and today he's a new man.
Let's but I have together for
Jesus Christ one more time.
Tebogo & Mother - Prophecy Testimony
So once again, we're just showing
this so that people of God
can really understand the extent of
what Jesus Christ has done
for our brother, and we give all the
glory to God that today he is free.
Jesus Christ has set him free from
that life that he was living before
and that spirit that was pushing
him into such a life has completely
been cast out by our Lord Jesus Christ.
One more time, people, let's put our hands
together for our Lord Jesus Christ!
Tebogo & Mother - Prophecy Testimony
Emmanuel!
People of God, my name is Regina Murake
and I'm from South Africa, I'm 57 years of age.
This is my son Tebogo, he is quite a charming boy.
He was quite a charming boy when he grew up,
and it happened that because I was staying with...
The man that I was staying with was not his father.
So it happened that he grew up with my father.
That is why most of the things that he said I don't know.
But I made it a point that he would get everything that he wanted.
I used to go to my place,, to my
father's place and buy food for him,
make sure that he goes to school and all that.
So the things that he said about
several time being jailed -
I don't know about it - I only know about one incident.
That's when I went there and then I
bailed him, he got out.
I tried to speak to him all the time.
When you speak to him, it is like
he listens, he understands
but immediately he goes away,
he does his own things there
which I didn't know. Actually, I
knew that there was something
wrong that he was doing because there was a time
when I was talking to him and he said:
"Mom, I need time to live my life, let me live my life."
Because it was like I wanted him
to live the way I want him to.
So I told him that it's okay: "But when things are not going
well with you remember that you've got a mother.
And I will always accept you and help you."
So he went away because he was not staying with me,
by then he was staying at my other brother's house.
So he was staying there with his girlfriend. All these things
started and happened whilst he was there
because he was at the university.
And then that's when I started to realize that
there was something wrong that he was doing
and I always told him that there was
something that was not right with him.
Then it took quite a time that he didn't come to me
because he said he wanted to live his own life.
That time he came back he was full of tattoos,
I felt so bad because the first thing
that he did it was that he was a Rastafarian.
He used to have big dreadlocks and those
dukes that they put a tie on their heads.
And I told him that I didn't like that
but he said this is the life that he chose.
That's when he told me that he wanted to live his own life.
And then after quite a time, that's when he
came now with tattoos all over his body.
For quite a time I knew that he needed help.
But I'm not a person who's used to charms and all that,
some people would advised me: "Go to so-and-so,
your son needs deliverance, your
son needs to be helped."
But I didn't know where to go, actually.
So five years back I got introduced to Emmanuel TV.
And I started watching it and something told me that
this is where I'm going to find a solution for myself
and actually for my son, I needed deliverance for him.
So it took me time to find a person who
I could connect so that we might come here.
After doing all the arrangements last year I told him that
I wanted him to come:
"There's a place that I want you to come with to.
It is a church and that's where
you're going to be delivered,
because I want you back, I want
the son that I gave birth to.
Not you, you are not the son that I gave birth to, satan is using you."
He agreed, and then he said: "Okay, mum,
I'll come on Saturday, all right?"
Saturday I waited for him - actually,
he said he'd come on Friday,
on Friday he didn't come, on Friday night
he said: "I will be there tomorrow morning."
And the next thing - tomorrow
morning I received a message to say:
"Mum, I think I'm the one who
caused these things to myself,
these are my problems, I'll see
to it that I sort myself out."
So I was so disappointed, I didn't respond to that.
During early this year his children came to visit and he
also came to visit, so I begged him to stay and sleep at home
because he was not used to sleeping at my place,
he would come and go.
Because his children were there,
we started sitting together,
and normally, my TV is always on Emmanuel.
And we would see it and we would talk and fortunately
most of the things that were coming up there,
were worse than what he thought he was doing.
He even said: "Things are worse than me,
I'm better than these people who appear here.
I thought that I am the worst but I think I'm better."
So he gradually got to like it and
then he disappeared again.
When you called him, he didn't pick up the phone - not at all.
So I didn't know what to do, but one
day I decided to say - I'm going to ask God.
I am definitely going to spend days asking
God for him to agree to come to SCOAN.
So I took days praying for that,
over that and then finally one morning
I woke up and then I decided that
I was going to call him that day.
I started taking my books, reading my books
and then I prayed. After praying I took my phone
and I sprayed the Morning water
on it and I said: "My God,
God of TB Joshua, this boy is going
to answer my phone today.
And he's going to come when I call him."
I wiped my phone so that it may not get damaged,
after that I called him - he picked up the phone.
I said: "I want to see you. When can you come?"
He said: "Okay, I will come tomorrow."
And tomorrow morning, he was there.
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Then when he came, I started telling him:
"I am going to SCOAN in June."
Actually I was saying it was in June, I want to
be there on the birthday of the prophet,
because mine is on the 16th, his is on the 19th of June.
I said I want us to be there.
And then I told him and then we
stayed and we watched Emmanuel TV.
We spoke about a lot of things.
That's when I gave him money to go
and do the passport, after a few days
I called him because I knew how he was.
So I called him: "Did you make the passport?"
He said: "Yes, mum, am just waiting for
the call to say I must go and fetch it."
After two-three weeks I called him:
"No, I haven't yet collected it."
Until finally he said: "You know, mom, I spent that money."
And I gave him money other than for that.
And then I said: "Okay, this time I think you must come
with that site so that we do that that site."
And he definitely did come, we did the passport,
he also didn't have his ID, we had to do another ID now.
But from there I didn't trust him still, he went away,
he came back again and then when he came back,
we sat and then we watched Emmanuel TV,
and then I told him that - one day I told him that
our date has come out:
"When can you be able to come
because we are leaving in three days."
He said: "Okay, I'll be there tomorrow."
The next morning at about 8 o'clock he appeared.
It was very early in the morning.
I looked at him but he was looking strange.
I just greeted him, and then I went
into another room. When I came back,
he was now okay and I said:
"You definitely are ready."
Because he had everything.
That's when I started to realize that we were coming here.
And remember, I was also sick for three months
I was very sick - all my joints.
I was always sleeping because I was very sick,
I needed deliverance and I needed healing too.
Fortunately, when I came here, I got healed -
the prophet touched me and then I got healed.
I was happy, I was healed and then of
all of a sudden
I didn't see the Prophet touching
him because I was all over the place by then.
But then I heard the Prophet calling him,
saying there's a man with tattoos and he is a thief.
I just jumped, because I would see sit at that side,
I just jumped and said: "Thank you, Lord. This is my day."
"This is the day the Lord has made for me to get delivered and my son to be delivered."
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
We can really see, it was indeed God's
time to restore this family completely.
And madam, ever since that prophecy
and deliverance your son received,
can you just tell us the changes
you've witnessed in his life?
Actually we were privileged
to stay for another week here at Synagogue.
Free accommodation, free food.
That's when I realized that God is with us.
God is really with us and when we talked about it,
he was excited to say: "When I come out of here,
I'll be perfect that other week is not just for fun.
It is really where God is working within us."
And then while we were staying here
he was always on his books, reading the Bible,
coming for classes and even in
the class I would just look at him:
what is he doing there? He was taking notes.
He was responding, he was asking questions.
And I said: "Now this is my boy, he is okay."
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
We give all the glory to God for what He has done
in the life of this family. And madam,
what is your word of advice to
viewers around the world
with what the Lord has done for
you and your son?
My word of advice to the parents out there
is that it's quite important to
stay with your children.
Be there for them. Yes, other
people can look after your children.
Don't judge the situation that we are living in,
make it a point that your children
are always with you so that
so that you see every movement that they make.
Because I think if I was around him,
he wouldn't have gone so far.
It is because I was not there most of the time,
and sometimes they wouldn't even tell me that sometimes
he was not sleeping at home because he was jailed and all that.
I didn't know why, it's just now that I hear about that.
So it is highly important that we stay with our children,
we teach our children about the Word of God,
we ensure that they are here next to us
and make sure that they come to church,
they know God, they work for God, we
pray together and do everything together.
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
And we just want to hear a final
word from our brother as well.
My advice will be to my colleagues
and my friends out there.
I know, some of them are watching me.
You know, out there - it's easier
to die than to live.
So put your trust in God, even if you have problems,
some of the problems you can't handle them.
Just put all your problems into Jesus,
only Jesus can change your life.
Thank You!
Amen, let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ.
Just a final question brother, you
said before you had the impression
that perhaps because of your appearance with the tattoos
that you would be condemned or
be looked down upon in the church.
What is your word of advice to
people who may be watching right now
with a similar thought - they feel that perhaps,
because of the way they look, their appearance
they will not be accepted in the house of God.
What do you really want to advise such people as well?
Well, I'll say don't look at the outside,
just look at the inside.
Because that's where God lives,
He actually looks at the inside of a human being.
Amen, let's put our hands together
for Jesus Christ one more time!
TT: Lizz Ndung'u 28/07/2018
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 07/08/2018